Privacy Policy Personal Data Protection
=======================================

Table of contents
-----------------

[II. Sendinblue Inc. Privacy Policy (Users incorporated in USA, Canada, Australia and New-Zealand)](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#privacysibinc)

If the legal entity you represent or act on behalf of is incorporated in the **USA, Canada, Australia or New Zealand**, the following terms are applicable to you: [Sendinblue Inc. Privacy Policy](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#privacysibinc)

If you are a California resident, this latter Privacy Policy (II) shall also be applicable.

I. Privacy Policy Personal Data Protection
------------------------------------------

This is the Privacy Notice for **Sendinblue SAS** (collectively **referred to as** “**Brevo**,” “**us**,” “**our**,” or “**we**”).

In the course of its activity and for the purposes of providing the Services (as defined in our General Terms of Use), Brevo is required to collect and process the personal data of its users (hereafter referred to as the “Users”).

This privacy policy, implemented by Brevo, is intended to provide the Users with a summary and overview of the processing of personal data carried out by Brevo.

Brevo attaches particular importance to the respect for the privacy of the Users and of the confidentiality of their personal data, and is thus committed to processing the data in compliance with the applicable laws and regulations, and in particular Law No. 78-17 of 6 January 1978 relating to Information Technology, Data Files and Civil Liberties (hereafter referred to as the “Data Protection Act”), and Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data (hereafter referred to as the “GDPR”).

### Definitions

**Personal data:** any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, that is, a person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an identification number or to one or more elements specific to that person.

**Processing of personal data:** any operation or any set of operations relating to personal data, whatever the process used, and in particular the collection, recording, organisation, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, as well as locking, erasure, or destruction.

**Cookie :** a cookie is a piece of information placed on the hard drive of Internet users by the server of the site they visit. It contains several pieces of data: the name of the server which installed it, an identifier in the form of a unique number, and possibly an expiry date. This information is sometimes stored on the computer in a simple text file that a server accesses to read and save pieces of information.

### Data Controller – DPO

The data controller for the processing of the personal data referred to herein is Brevo, a simplified joint stock company with a share capital of 387,722 Euros, registered with the Paris Trade and Companies Register under number 498 019 298 and whose registered office is located at 106 boulevard Haussmann, 75008 Paris, France.

Brevo has appointed a Data Protection Officer who can be contacted at the following address: [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### Data collected

Brevo collects data from Users in order to make the Services for which they have subscribed to the platform available to them.

The mandatory or optional nature of the data provided (in order to complete the Users’ registration and to render the Services) is indicated at the time of collection by an asterisk.

In addition, certain data is collected automatically as a result of the User’s actions on the site (see the paragraph on cookies).

#### Purposes

The personal data collected by Brevo during the provision of the Services is necessary for the performance of the contracts concluded with the Users, or to allow Brevo to pursue its legitimate interests while respecting the rights of the Users. Certain data may also be processed based on the Users’ consent.

The purposes for which Brevo processes data are the following:

* commercial and accounting management of the contract;
* management of customer acquisition and marketing activities;
* detection of malicious behaviour (fraud, phishing, spam, etc.);
* the improvement of the Users path on the site;
* more generally, any purpose referred to in Article 2 of Deliberation No. 2012-209 of 21 June 2012 creating a simplified standard for the automated processing of personal data relating to the management of users and prospects.

#### Recipients of the data

The personal data collected is intended for Brevo’s commercial and accounting departments. It may be transmitted to Brevo’s subsidiaries, or to third-party data processors which Brevo is authorized to use within the context of the performance of its Services.

In this context, personal data may be transferred to an EU or non-EU country. Brevo implements guarantees ensuring the protection and security of this data, in compliance with applicable rules and regulations.

Brevo does not transfer or rent personal data to third parties for marketing purposes without the express consent of the Users of Brevo.

In addition, personal data may only be disclosed to third parties for purposes other than marketing in the following cases:

* with their authorisation;
* at the request of the competent legal authorities, upon judicial request, or in the context of a legal dispute.

#### Data retention period

To satisfy its legal obligations or in order to have the necessary elements to assert its rights, Brevo will be able to retain the data under the conditions established by applicable rules and regulations.

Thus, personal data collected by Brevo relating to the identity and contact details of its Users is retained for a maximum period of two years after the termination of the contractual relationship for Users that are customers, or from their collection by the data controller or the last contact from the Users that are prospects, for the data relating to the latter.

The termination of the contractual relationship is understood as the express termination of the contract by the User, or the non-use of Brevo Services for a period of five years.

#### Rights of Users

In accordance with applicable rules, the Users have the right to access and rectify their personal data, which enables them to rectify, complete, update, or delete data that is inaccurate, incomplete, ambiguous, or outdated, or whose collection, use, communication, or storage is prohibited.

The Users also have the right to request the limitation of the processing, and to oppose on legitimate grounds the processing of their personal data. The User may also communicate instructions on the fate of their personal data in the event of their death.

Where applicable, the User may request the portability of their personal data or, where the legal basis for the processing is consent, withdraw their consent at any time.

The Users may exercise their rights by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or a letter to:

**  
Sendinblue SAS  — DPO Team  
106 boulevard Haussmann, 75008 Paris, France  
**

These requests shall be processed within a maximum period of 30 days.

The Users may also at any time modify the data pertaining to them by logging on to [https://www.brevo.com](https://www.brevo.com/) and clicking on “edit my profile” or by contacting the customer relations department at [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

The Users may unsubscribe from the Brevo newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe links in each of these emails.

In the event of a dispute, the Users may file a complaint with the CNIL, for which contact details may be found at [https://www.cnil.fr.](https://www.cnil.fr./)

The Users may access detailed information on the use of their personal data, in particular concerning the purposes of the processing, the legal bases enabling Brevo to process the data, its storage period, its recipients, and, where applicable, its transfer to a country outside the European Union as well as the related compliance guarantees put in place for such transfers. To do so, the User can send their request by email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/dpo@brevo.com).

#### Additional terms regarding the use of the Inbox Feature

Brevo’s platform complies with the [Google API Services user Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements. Any use and transfer of information received from Google API’s from Brevo’s platform to any other applications will require to adhere to [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements.

Notwithstanding anything else in the present Privacy Policy, if the User provides Brevo access to their Gmail user data, Brevo shall:

* only use access to read, write, modify, or control Gmail message bodies (including attachments), metadata, headers, and settings, allowing Brevo to provide a web email client for the Users to compose, send, read, and process emails;
* never transfer such data to other parties unless doing so is necessary to provide and improve these features, comply with applicable law, or as part of a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets;
* in no way use such data for its management of customer acquisition and marketing activities;
* in no way use such data to serve advertisements;
* not allow humans to read this data unless Brevo has the User’s affirmative agreement for specific messages, doing so is necessary for security purposes such as investigating abuse, to comply with applicable law, or for Brevo’s internal operations, and even then, only when the data have been aggregated and anonymized.

### Cookies

For more information about how Brevo handles cookies, please visit our [cookie policy page](https://www.brevo.com/legal/cookies/).

### Security

Brevo has taken all necessary precautions to preserve the security of personal data and, in particular, to prevent it from being accessed by unauthorized third parties, distorted, or damaged.

These measures include the following:

* Multi-level firewall.
* Proven solutions for anti-virus protection and detection of intrusion attempts.
* Encrypted data transmission using SSL/https/VPN technology.
* Tier 3 and PCI DSS certified data centres.

In addition, access to processing data on behalf of Brevo by the receiving third-party services requires authentication of the persons accessing the data, by means of an individual access code and password, that is sufficiently robust and regularly renewed.

Data transmitted over unsecured communication channels is subject to technical measures designed to make such data incomprehensible to any unauthorised person.

Any questions about the security of the Brevo website can be directed to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### Modification of the Privacy Policy

Brevo reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy to comply with changes in the applicable laws and regulations.

The Users shall be notified of any changes made to this policy via our website or by email at least thirty days prior, when possible, to their entry into force.

### Contact

Any questions about Brevo’s Privacy Policy can be directed by email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by mail to:

**Sendinblue SAS – DPO Team**  
****106 boulevard Haussmann, 75008 Paris**, France**

II. Brevo North America Privacy Policy
--------------------------------------

For users incorporated in USA, Canada, Australia and New-Zealand

This is the Privacy Notice for **Sendinblue Inc.** dba **Sendinblue**, (collectively **referred to as** “**Brevo**,” “**us**,” “**our**,” or “**we**”). It explains how we collect and use information on brevo.com and other websites we own or operate (collectively, the “**Site**”), our suite of software and professional services owned and operated by Sendinblue Inc. or its affiliates and/or delivered under the business name Brevo (the “**Software**”) for managing contacts and designing, implementing, and administering email, sms, and certain other marketing programs , our other digital properties or services, and your communications with us by any means (collectively with the Site, Software, and Programs, the “**Services**”). Please read this Privacy Notice carefully to understand our privacy practices.

**This Privacy Notice applies to Brevo’s activities in, or for Users that are incorporated in, the United States, Canada, New-Zealand and Australia, and includes supplemental notices specific to residents of [California](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#california). If you are a resident of or located in the European Union, please instead review our** [**Privacy Policy Personal Data Protection**](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#eu)**.**

This Privacy Notice is governed by and part of our General Conditions of Use of Brevo Services (the “**General Terms**”). Your use of our Services is subject to this Privacy Notice and our General Terms, including its applicable limitations on damages and the provisions regarding resolution of disputes. Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Notice have the meanings given to them in the General Terms. Any additional notices we may provide you about our privacy practices will be considered to form part of this Privacy Notice.

Note that this Privacy Notice **DOES NOT** apply to any third-party websites, platforms, or activities, such as a Customer’s websites or marketing practices. If you are a Contact of our Customer(s), your use of a Customer’s website or receipt of marketing communications from a Brevo Customer is governed by the Customer’s privacy notice, and Brevo has no control over their privacy practices.

### Consent

By using or accessing our Services in any manner, you acknowledge and accept this Privacy Notice, and you consent to Brevo’s collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described below. If you do not agree with this Privacy Notice, do not use our Services.

### Personal information

As used in this Privacy Notice, “**Personal Information**” means information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or household. Personal Information falls into various categories, such as identifiers, protected information, sensitive personal information (e.g., social security number, race, health data, or union membership), biometrics, commercial history, employment-related data, nonpublic educational information, internet activity, or inferences drawn to create a consumer profile. The use of sensitive personal data on the Platform and as part of the Services is forbidden.

Personal Information **does not** include (i) publicly available information (ii) aggregate information, meaning data about a group or category of services or users from which individual identities and other Personal Information has been removed; or (iii) deidentified information that cannot reasonably be used to infer information about, or otherwise be linked to, a particular consumer.

### Collection and use of personal information

The types of Personal Information we collect and how it is used depends on how you interact with us, such as a Site visitor, a Brevo customer using the Services or representative of a customer (a “**Customer**”) or as a Customer’s marketing contact (“**Contact**”).  Brevo only collects, uses, retains, and shares Personal Information as reasonably necessary and proportionate to provide the Services or for other purposes that we disclose to you and are compatible with the context of how we collected your Personal Information. We will update this Privacy Notice or otherwise notify you before we collect additional categories of Personal Information from consumers or use such Personal Information for purposes that are incompatible with the purpose stated at the time of collection.

**Categories of Personal Information**

During the preceding 12 months, we have collected these categories of Personal Information:

* Identifiers (e.g., name, address, phone number, email address, password, IP address)
* Employment-related information (e.g., current or past employment)
* Commercial information (e.g., purchases considered or completed)
* Internet activity (e.g., interactions with the Site and Platform)

**Sources of Collection**

We collect Personal Information from the following sources and use that information as described below:

* **Directly from you when you contact us or place an order.** If you contact us via the Site or by email, phone, or other means to request information or support, we will collect your name, contact information, and employment-related information as needed to respond to your inquiry. If you place an order with us, we will use a PCI-compliant payment processor to collect and process your payment information. You may opt-in to save your payment information for future orders, but this is not required. We collect this information with your consent, and we use it to respond to your inquiries, communicate with you about your order status, or for the purposes stated at the time of collection.
* **Directly from you when you create a Customer account.** If you create a Customer account, we will collect your name, email address, company name, and require you to choose a password to login. We collect this information with your consent, and we use it to provide the Services, identify and administer your account, and communicate with you about the Services. You have the right to opt-out of communications from us, but you cannot opt out of communications that we send you regarding your account.
* **From our Customers about their Contacts.** Brevo Services enables Customers to promote their brands through email, SMS, chat, and other types of marketing communications. Customers may choose to input their Contacts’ Personal Information into the Services to send them marketing communications. Brevo collects Contacts’ Personal Information to fulfill our contractual obligations as a service provider to the Customer. A Customer’s processing of Contacts’ Personal Information via the Services is subject to the Customer’s privacy practices, not ours. Brevo is not responsible for any Customer’s compliance with applicable privacy laws, or a Customer’s obligations to related to their Contacts’ privacy rights.
* **Automatically from you when you visit the Site or use our Software.** When you visit our Site or use our Software, we automatically collect data about your internet activity such as your IP address, internet service provider description, information about the type of device used to access our Site, and browser information. Like most online services, the Site and Platform use cookies as described in our [Cookie List](https://www.brevo.com/legal/cookies/). We collect this information to achieve our legitimate interest of facilitating online communication or when it is strictly necessary to provide an online Service. We use this information to help diagnose problems with and secure our servers, to administer the proper functioning and legitimate use of our Site, generate analytics and statistics. With your prior consent, we also use that information to improve the nature and marketing of the Services. The Customer warrants that it will provide all necessary information to the relevant natural persons, and obtain all necessary consents from them, as required by applicable data protection and electronic communication laws, in order to allow Brevo to lawfully deploy cookies and similar tracking technologies and to lawfully collect data from the devices of Contacts and Service Users. These tracers might include pixels and web beacons. The exact list of cookies and tracking devices is available [here](https://www.brevo.com/legal/cookies/).

**Children’s Privacy**

Brevo does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 16. However, we cannot control the Personal Information our Customer’s collect. If a Customer chooses to input Personal Information of children under age 16 on the Services, that Customer does so under its own privacy practices, not ours. Brevo is not responsible for a Customer’s failure to comply with any law designed to protect children or any other law governing the Customer’s use of our Services. Please contact the Customer directly if you have questions about their privacy practices. As part of our commitment to your privacy, we encourage you to contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) if you believe we might have collected any information online from a child under 16, or if you are aware of any unauthorized submission of information to us. Brevo reserves the right to delete any information from our systems if we discover it was improperly collected.

**Retention of Personal Information**

* **Personal Information about Contacts.** The Customer is responsible for determining a data retention period of the Contact Personal Information and to operate the deletion when necessary. If the Customer does not take action, Brevo retains all categories of Personal Information we collect only as long as your Brevo account remains active or as necessary to provide you with the Services you request.
* **Commercial relationship personal information.** We may also retain and use Personal Information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We regularly review and deidentify unnecessary Personal Information and other data and we periodically deidentify unused accounts.
* **Cookie Data.** Any Personal Information that we may collect using cookies or other tracing technologies is retained on our system for 12 months. In some cases, we may be required to retain this Personal Information for longer or shorter periods to meet our regulatory obligations, in which case we will retain the data for the required period.

**Other Uses**

In addition to the specific uses described above, Brevo might also use your Personal Information to:

* Provide, maintain, and improve our Services and user experience.
* Send you support and administrative messages.
* Monitor your compliance with any of your agreements with us. 
* Detect, investigate, and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities and protect the rights and property of Company and others.
* Protect your privacy and enforce this Privacy Notice.
* If we believe it is necessary, to identify, contact, or bring legal action against persons who may be causing injury to you, to us, or to others.
* Comply with a law, regulation, legal process, or court order.
* Fulfill any other purpose to which you consent.

### Disclosing personal information

**Categories**

In the preceding 12 months, Brevo has disclosed all categories of Personal Information that we collected for a business purpose.  

**Recipients**

Brevo may disclose Personal Information to the recipients described below, or to other recipients with your permission or as required by law. 

* **Service Providers:** Brevo uses a variety of service providers such as data hosting companies, analytics services, email hosting services, and payment processors. The type of information that we share with a service provider will depend on the service that they provide to us. Our service providers are subject to contractual agreements that protect your Personal Information, and we require all service providers to maintain confidentiality standards that are commercially reasonable to ensure the security of your Personal Information. 
* **Government Agencies:** Occasionally Brevo may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personal Information to governmental authorities. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our Services for illegal activities. Brevo reserves the right to disclose Personal Information to law enforcement and other governmental agencies, at our sole discretion in connection with an investigation of any matter that is illegal or that could expose Brevo or our affiliates to liability.
* **Cookie Information Recipients:** In some cases, we may allow specific cooperating entities to use [cookies](https://www.brevo.com/legal/cookies/) or similar technologies to collect non-personal data from your browser or device for measurement purposes. Receipt and use of such information are subject to each cookie information recipient’s Privacy Notice.
* **Affiliates and Third Parties:** We may disclose the Personal Information we collect about you to our affiliates like a parent company or subsidiaries. For example, we share Personal Information for Customer support purposes, marketing, or technical operations. Under specific circumstances, we may disclose Personal Information to certain third parties as permitted by applicable law, for example: if we go through a business transition (e.g., merger, acquisition, or asset sale); to comply with a legal requirement or a court order; when we believe it is appropriate to take action regarding illegal activities or prevent fraud or harm to any person; to exercise or defend our legal claims; or for any other reason with your consent.

**Aggregated and Deidentified Information**

We reserve the right to disclose aggregated, anonymized, or deidentified information about any individuals with affiliated or nonaffiliated entities for marketing, advertising, research, or other purposes, without restriction. For example, we may share reports showing trends about the general use of our Services without identifying an individual. 

### Your privacy rights

Brevo believes you should have the ability to control the Personal Information we collect and hold about you on your own. You can use the methods described below to control how we collect and use your Personal Information. 

* **Customer Accounts:** Customers can change or delete the Personal Information in their accounts at any time by signing into the Platform and editing information or changing settings. Brevo may offer instructions to guide Customers in making additional changes. A Customer can delete all of their Personal Information on Brevo by closing the account. 
* **Contact Information:** Customers can change or delete their Contacts’ Personal Information at any time by signing into the Platform and editing information or changing settings. Brevo may offer instructions to guide Customers in making additional changes. If a Contact submits a Consumer Privacy Request directly to Brevo, we will relay the request to the applicable Customer for further processing. 
* **Email Communications:** If you are a Customer or Site visitor, we may send you marketing emails about the Services. Customers may also receive informational or support emails from us. If you do not wish to receive these emails, you may change your preferences via the links provided in the emails or by sending a request to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to be removed from our email list. Note that if you opt-out of marketing communications, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.
* **Texting Consent:** If you provide us with your wireless phone number, you consent to Brevo sending you informational or service text messages. However, we will only send you marketing text messages if you opt-in to receive these notifications from us. For all Brevo text messages, the number of texts you receive will depend on the Services you use and the information you request from us. You can unsubscribe from Brevo text messages by replying STOP or UNSUBSCRIBE to any of these text messages. Messaging and data charges may apply to any text message you receive or send. Please contact your wireless carrier if you have questions about messaging or data charges.
* **Do Not Track:** Do Not Track signals are signals sent through a browser informing us that you do not want to be tracked. Currently, our systems do not recognize browser “do-not-track” requests. If this changes in the future, we will update this Privacy Notice.

Depending on where you reside, you may have additional privacy rights or be entitled to additional controls over your Personal Information. Please see our supplemental notices specific to residents of [**California**](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#california). 

**Consumer Privacy Requests**

If you wish to exercise your privacy rights beyond the methods available through the Platform, or if you want to express concerns, lodge a complaint, or request information, please submit a verifiable Consumer Privacy Request using our online **Consumer Privacy Request** form or by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Note that if you are a Customer’s Contact, then we process your Personal Information as a service provider to the Customer and we cannot fulfill your request directly. In that case, we will relay your request to the appropriate Customer for further processing and fulfillment, provided that we have sufficient information to do so.

Brevo can only fulfill a Consumer Privacy Request when we have sufficient information to verify that the requester is the person or an authorized representative of the person about whom we have collected Personal Information, and to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to the request. We do not charge a fee to process or respond to a verifiable request unless we have legal grounds to do so. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.

We endeavor to respond to Consumer Privacy Requests in accordance with the requirements of the law applicable to your jurisdiction. Depending on the circumstances and the nature of your request, we may be unable to fulfill your request in part or in whole, for example, if your request falls within a statutory exception or if fulfilling your request would prevent us from complying with a statutory or contractual obligation. 

### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

This section provides residents of the State of California (“**California Consumers**”) with the disclosures and notices required under the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“**CCPA**”). The following paragraphs apply solely to California Consumers and describe the specific rights afforded under the CCPA. California Consumers may exercise the following rights over their Personal Information, subject to any exceptions and limitations that may apply:

* **Right to Know:** You have the right to request that we disclose information to you about our collection and use of your Personal Information, such as: (i) the categories of Personal Information we have collected about you; (ii) the categories of sources for the Personal Information we have collected about you; (iii) our business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling or sharing your Personal Information; (iv) the categories of third parties with whom we disclose your Personal Information; and (v) a list of specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you. If a business sells or shares your Personal Information, you also You also have the right to ask the company to disclose the categories of your Personal Information sold or shared and the categories of third parties to whom that Personal information was sold or shared, as well as the categories of Personal information disclosed for a business purpose and the categories of recipients of that information. Brevo is only required to respond to two disclosure requests from you within a 12-month period. 
* **Right to Access.** You have the right to request that we provide you with access to specific pieces of Personal Information we have collected about you over the past 12 months (also called a data portability request). If you submit a right to access request, we will provide you with copies of the requested Personal Information in a portable and readily usable format. Please note that Brevo may be prohibited by law from disclosing copies of certain Personal Information when the disclosure would create a substantial, articulable, and unreasonable risk to the security of the information, our systems, or your account. We are only required by law to respond to two access requests from you within a 12-month period.  
* **Right to Correct.** If you discover that we maintain inaccurate Personal Information about you, or if your Personal Information changes, please inform us and we will update our records to reflect the correct information.
* **Right to Deletion.** You have the right to request that we delete Personal Information that we collected from you and retained, with certain exceptions. Brevo may permanently delete, deidentify, or aggregate the Personal Information in response to a request for deletion. If you submit a right to deletion request, we will confirm the Personal Information to be deleted prior to its deletion, and we will notify you when your request is complete.
* **No Selling Personal Information.**  Brevo does not and will never sell your Personal Information to third parties.. 
* **Sharing Personal Information.** Brevo may share Personal Information we collect via cookies and other tracing technologies with third parties for cross-contextual behavioral advertising purposes. You can opt-out of this sharing by adjusting your cookie settings or by submitting a **Consumer Privacy Request**.
* **Limited Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information.** Brevo does not seek to collect sensitive Personal Information from any consumer. If a Customer chooses to input sensitive Personal Information into the Platform, we will not use or disclose Sensitive Personal Information for the purpose of inferring characteristics about any consumer. If this ever changes in the future, we will update this Privacy Notice and provide you with methods to limit use and disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information. However, we have no control over whether our Customers may use or disclose their contacts’ sensitive Personal information for any particular purpose. If you are a Contact of our Customers, please direct any questions about your sensitive Personal Information to the respective Customer. 
* **Right to Nondiscrimination.** We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by law, we will not: (i) deny you goods or services; (ii) charge you different prices or rates for goods or services; (iii) provide you a different level or quality of goods or services; or (iv) suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services, because you exercised a right under the CCPA.
* **Right to Disclosure of Marketing Information.** Under California’s Shine the Light Act (Ca. Civ. Code § 1798.83-1798.84), California Consumers are entitled to request certain disclosures about Personal Information sharing with affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes. Please contact us if you wish to obtain these disclosures.

California Consumers may exercise these rights over their Personal Information by logging into their Customer account or by sending us a verifiable [**Consumer Privacy Request**](https://www.brevo.com/legal/privacypolicy/#consumerprivacyrequest), subject to any exceptions and limitations that may apply. 

**Employee Data Exception**

In many cases, the Personal Information we collect about you is in a business-to-business context when you are acting as an employee to a Customer or potential Customer in the performance of your job duties. Please note that Personal Information collected and used in this context is not protected under the CCPA. 

### Data security

Brevo implements reasonable and appropriate security procedures and practices to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized or illegal access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure. We employ a series of security measures, including a multi-level firewall, encryption, and anti-virus and intrusion detection solutions. All data is stored on secure servers in Tier 3 and PCI DSS certified data centers and is only accessible to our personnel and contractors via authentication measures. We ensure that Brevo employees, contractors, and agents responsible for handling your inquiries are informed of applicable privacy law requirements and we restrict access to those who need that information in order to process it. 

Please note, however, that no transmission of data over the internet is 100% secure. We cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will not defeat our security measures or use your Personal Information for improper purposes. We also have no control over our Customers’ security measures or practices, and we make no representations or guarantees that your Personal Information is secure once transmitted or stored on their systems.

It is your responsibility to keep your Customer account secure from unauthorized access. We encourage our Customers to take steps to protect against unauthorized access to their accounts, such as choosing a robust password, keeping the password private, and signing off after using a shared computer or other device. Brevo is not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords, or any unauthorized activity on your account.

Additional terms regarding the use of the Inbox Feature
-------------------------------------------------------

Brevo’s platform complies with the [Google API Services user Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements. Any use and transfer of information received from Google API’s from Brevo’s platform to any other applications will require to adhere to [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements.

### Third party websites

The Services may contain links to websites owned or operated by third parties. We have no ability to control, and we are not responsible for, the privacy and data collection, use, and disclosure practices of third-party websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each website that collects your Personal Information. 

### Changes to this privacy notice

We may periodically update this Privacy Notice. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by updating this posting or by posting notice in the Services. The date that this Privacy Notice was last revised is identified at the top of the page. Your continued use of the Services after the effective date will be subject to the new Privacy Notice. You are responsible for periodically checking this Privacy Notice for changes.

### Contact Brevo

If you have questions about our privacy practices or would like to make a complaint, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection), or by mail at Brevo 1402 Third Avenue, #301, Seattle, WA 98101.

For UK based data subjects, processors, controllers, and the ICO: The representative for the UK according to Article 27 of the UK GPDR can be reached by email: [\[email protected\]](https://www.brevo.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
